VALON RAMA FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER

VRAMA21@GMAIL.COM

PHILADELPHIA, PA

609.204.3407

VRAMA21 VRAMA21

VRAMA21.GITHUB.IO/PORTFOLIO

TECHNOLOGIES

Languages

Python, Javascript

Frontend

ReactJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Handlebars

Backend

Django, Flask, Express, NodeJS, REST API

Databases

MySQL, MongoDB, Postgres, SQLite

Other

Git, jQuery, JSON, Microsoft Suite, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

PROJECTS

Sheriff Sale

Sheriff Sale is an application that scrapes data for upcoming real-estate auctions in New Jersey. It fetches all associated data for each auction from other external sites such as Trulia and Zillow and aggregates the data into a central view for the user.

LetsPlayHockey

LetsPlayHockey is a resource for hockey players to find, create, and sign-up for local pick-up hockey games. Search players by their skill level, position, and/or their availability.

Flex Point-of-Sale

Flex Point-of-Sale is a restaurant point-of-sale application. The goal of this application is to bring in newer modern technologies to a category which has been out-of-date and lacked any recent innovations. Flex is built with the idea of complete flexibility. Flexbility to handle any test-case in the restaurant industry, and to handle it flawlessly to increase work productivity and reduce potential errors.

WORK EXPERIENCE

06/2016 - Present | Atlantic City, NJ

Manager/Supervisor | Marco Polo's Inc.

- Structured schedule for 10-15 employees.
- Managed inventory and stock bi-weekly.
- · Recruited, hired, and oversaw training of staff.
- Supervised all floor activity to maintain high standards of customer satisfaction.
- Shifted business strategies resulting in significant increases in sales and profits each year.
- Integrated, maintained, and upgraded Point-of-Sale software systems, producing higher efficiency and accuracy on delivering products.

09/2013 - 04/2014 | Philadelphia, PA

Software Quality Assurance Intern | National Board of Medical Examiners

- Constructed and executed test cases for web applications based on design specifications and requirements.
- Detected and documented software bugs and potential failure points.
- · Collaborated with developers, business analysts, and project managers to maintain the project timeline and deliverable.
- Ensured applications are fully functional, stable, and bug-free prior to deployment.

EDUCATION

UPenn LPS Coding Bootcamp

Fullstack Web Development

2011 - 2016 **Drexel University Computer Engineering**